André Walker - Curriculum Vitae

Summary

I'm a 24 year old software developer, and a passionate programmer since I was 13.

I have a solid understanding of Perl, as well as most of the main libraries and frameworks of the language. I'm a big fan of the Catalyst MVC framework, and how it helps making applications maintainable without being too opinionated. I use it mostly with the extremely powerful DBIx::Class ORM, and Text::Xslate or Template::Toolkit for web templates.

I've written a fair amount of code in Java and C, mostly for learning purposes. I have a good knowledge of front-end languages for the web, like HTML, JavaScript and CSS, and I have also worked for a few years with PHP.

One of my latest personal projects was setting up a media center and file server with a couple of single board computers, which I am still constantly tweaking.

Work Experience

Estante Virtual (January 2014 - present)

Estante Virtual is a Brazilian e-commerce with the largest collection of used books in the country. It works as a reseller of third-party bookstores.

My role was mostly focused on the shopping cart and processing payments, both for new features and maintenance of the code. I was responsible for developing a library to interface a new payment gateway that would be integrated in the website.

I faced a series of interesting challenges in the job, ranging from scalability to security, because of the volume of traffic and sales.

Google Summer of Code (May 2011 - August 2011)

I developed a project for the Google Summer of Code for The Perl Foundation called "Rework Catalyst component setup code", which was mentored by Tomas Doran and Eden Cardim.

My task was to use BreadBoard, an IOC framework for Perl, to load Catalyst components, making the component setup system more flexible and powerful. It was a great experience. Not only did I learn a lot about Catalyst internals, but I also learned how to write better tests and the importance of back-compatibility, with the help of my mentors and other developers in the project.

Freelance jobs (August 2010 - present)

While in university, I worked on several freelance projects, including developing a system for registrations in W3C events in Brazil, such as Web.br and WWW2013.

I developed several small systems and maintained websites for local companies. I also performed sysadmin tasks, setting up virtual private servers that handled up to 20k pageviews per day, and mail servers containing over 600 e-mail accounts.

Tactos (Advertising agency) (August 2009 - July 2010)

Tactos is a small advertising agency based in Americana, state of São Paulo. My job was to work on an proprietary CMS, and to create websites in PHP. I also developed a few internal tools, configured file servers, HTTP servers, and even worked on a couple of Delphi projects.

Skills

Programming

In Perl, I have experience with object oriented programming with Moose, Moo, and with the native Perl OO. I have maintained legacy Perl CGI scripts and mod_perl systems, and I have created and maintained modern Catalyst applications and web services, deployed with Starman and nginx.

While I am mostly a back-end developer, I have written and maintained JavaScript code. I have exposure to Dojo and jQuery, and I like the way AngularJS handles Inversion of Control and Dependency Injection.

I have also worked with PHP and some PHP-based software, such as WordPress and Magento, including the development of plugins and themes.

During my 3 years of technical secondary school and 4 years of university, I wrote a large amount of C, Java and Pascal code. Recently, I've been studying and experimenting with Haskell and OCaml in my free time, and I love the strict typing and elegant solutions they provide.

Databases

I have used extensively both MySQL and PostgreSQL for personal and commercial projects. I find sqitch to be an invaluable tool for tracking database changes, more flexible than most migration-style approaches.

System Administration

I use Linux exclusively for my personal computer and servers for around 10 years. I set up a personal mail server using Postfix and Dovecot, and my personal website with a custom GitHub Pages setup, having previously used for a while Amazon S3, CloudFront and Route 53. I am very confortable with the Linux command line and tools.

I have configured a few Apache, lighttpd and cherokee webservers in the past, but I am currently much more fond of nginx.

Open Source and Community

I am engaged in advocating Open Source. I have a very active GitHub profile with several of my personal projects, or forks, and I have contributed to a variety of Perl projects such as Catalyst, DBIx::Class, DBIx::Class::Schema::Loader, Text::Xslate, BreadBoard and others.

I have spoken in a few local Perl Monger technical events and YAPC's, and once organized a hackaton of about 25 people.

Education

- Bachelor in Computer Science, UFSCar University of São Carlos 2014
- Technical degree in Computer Science, COTUCA Technical High School of Campinas 2009

Contact

E-mail: andre@andrewalker.net

Skype: andrewalker.net